Akshitha Thorthi

akshithathorthi.9619@gmail.com | (786)-631-7635 | Florida, United States

Summary

Strategic Data Scientist versed in distilling and analyzing large data sets. Develops and delivers presentations detailing data findings. Articulate and collaborative with expertise in algorithm design and data collection. Flexible hard worker ready to learn and contribute to team success.

Skills

- C, Java, R, Python, Linux
- Efficient data management
- Data management
- Database Programming
- MS Office

- HTML, XML, SQL, MySQL
- System Administration
- Database updates
- Software applications
- Program evaluation

Experience

IBM India Private limited | Software Engineer | June 2019 – August 2021

- Developed user interfaces and display formats per customer requests and client-provided parameters.
- Created and reviewed operational database assets for software releases.
- Communicated traffic-related delays, mechanical issues and other problems affecting delivery times
- Delivered status reports to stakeholders for planning purposes.
- Distributed status reports to leadership team.
- Defined appropriate metrics and measurements to drive results.
- Enforced company policies, answered co-workers' questions and trained new personnel.
- Completed various reports and analyzed each report to decide where improvements could be made.

Accenture India Private Limited | Business Operations Associate | February 2018 – June 2019

- Communicated with clients regarding account status and project updates.
- Partnered with team members to identify and address challenges or opportunities.
- Facilitated meetings with customers and internal team members to communicate project updates.
- Recommended suggestions and improvements based on data analysis.
- Provided support to marketing team to assist development of new project materials.
- Reviewed and evaluated contract terms to maximize profit.
- Designed new operational processes and systems to achieve goals.

Educational Qualification

- Florida International University | Masters of Science | Data Science | August 2021- Present
 Data Science
- Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University | Bachelor of Technology | May 2017
 Computer Science and Engineering

Certifications

- Oracle Academy Database Programming with SQL
- Cisco Women Rock IT Student
- IBM Cloud Transformation Essentials
- Cloud security Architect and engineer fundamentals
- IBM Cloud Essentials